on this video I would like to show you
how we can replace PowerPoint with
markdown nvs code Mark or markdown
presentation ecosystem takes the text
that we write and turns it into a
beautiful PowerPoint presentation PDF
and even an interactive website the
fastest way to get started with Mark is
by using it as a vs code extension open
your vs code go to extensions menu and
install it after you do that open an
empty markdown file and write down this
code to enable Mark that section of my
markdown file is called the front matter
and here is where we can configure and
customize our presentation after that
you can get started writing your first
slide using normal markdown to see a
preview of your presentation click the
open preview button on your vs code top
right corner and as you will see Mark is
taking the markdown code that you wrote
and generating a presentation for you
super over cool to create another slide
just write dash dash dash and Mark will
do the rest apart from the default one
marp ships with two other teams called
on cover and Gaia which we can enable
from our front matter and if we use the
class directive we can get a dark mode
by writing invert we can also ask Mark
to add page numbers to our presentation
by using the paginate directive using
directives we can add a footer or header
to all our slides and because we are in
markdown we can use markdown features
like bolt and italic text formatting you
can customize each slide independently
as well by writing a comment on the
slides you want to change with the new
Styles and configuration we can also add
images to our slides using markdown
syntax and we can use any of the super
nice image utilities that marp has we
can add a background image to our Slide
by using the BG keyword we can size our
images and we can also add effects to
them like blur sepia brightness contrast
box Shadow among many others you can
also position images however you like
Mark also supports code highlighting and
it makes the code look beautiful as well
there are many other things that you can
do with Mark you can download and use a
community theme and you can even use
your own CSS and HTML on the slides if
you want to but the coolest thing about
marp in my opinion is what happens when
you finish the presentation and Export
it after you're done and you want to
export your presentation marker gives
you three options you can export it like
a PDF a PowerPoint or an HTML slide deck
the first tool will give you a PDF or a
PowerPoint with the slides that you made
as images but when you choose to export
it for the web you will receive a single
dot HTML file that any browser can open
and that HTML file is interactive you
will have arrows to click a button to go
full screen and important to trigger
pre-center View and something that is
super cool is that because we used the
asterisk symbol when making our list
items on the web each one of these items
will be revealed one by one which I
think it's a really nice detail if we
used dashes rather than Asterix they
will all show up at the same time I
personally like the HTML export much
much much more than the other one
because you can just upload the HTML to
your website and people can see your
presentation from their phones you can
include links gifs videos Etc and
because all you need to open your
presentation is a browser you also don't
have to worry about the computer at your
school or company having PowerPoint
installed or if it's a Mac or not and
that's it for this video let me know in
the comments if you found it useful and
if you are using Mark already share your
tips and tricks on how to use it well
and don't forget that if you want to
learn things like JavaScript python
react react native go Dart flutter among
many others for absolutely free all you
have to do is click the link below to
join any of our many free courses that
you can take right now for free with me
click the link below and I will see you
then
see you on the next one bye
[Music]